hey everyone welcome back to this Tosca
automation playlist and today I am going
to talk about a Tosca best practices
now we are going to go through a list of
different best practices although there
are several defined in the classcenter
support website I'm going to take you
through top 10 best practices during
this series of videos so we are going to
start off with the first best practice
in this particular video and then we'll
continue doing many more uh in the
coming up videos
so before we start I would recommend you
to subscribe to our channel so that you
don't miss out on the next video
now coming to the Tosca best practice
number one
and it is about naming conventions
now this could be useful if you are
working on a real project or if you are
preparing for your interviews or even if
you are just practicing with placenta
stoska for your test automation
naming conventions are very important
whenever you are working with any
automation project no matter which tool
do you use okay you have to follow some
naming conventions and this practice is
also followed in uh development in
testing or in any other field okay so it
is very important to have proper naming
conventions and then it is also followed
across the team not just by you okay so
proper and consistent naming conventions
should be used for module test case or
desktop names then present testoster
okay so what will happen if you don't
follow these naming conventions
so what will happen if we don't follow
this best practice
well in the coming up time once you
start building your automation you will
realize that it will become difficult to
maintain your automation project if you
don't follow naming conventions also if
you are working in a team and if
everybody is following their own naming
conventions for different objects like
modules test cases or test step names
then someone joining new to the team
will never be able to recognize what
this actual module does and then there
will be duplicate modules or test cases
created even though they exist in the
project
so the whole purpose of uh the framework
will fail because then there will be
duplications there will be higher
maintenance there will be less
reusability
and also the project won't be readable
and won't be easy to use for a newcomer
right so there are a lot of
disadvantages and there are lots of
advantages if you follow the best
practice okay
so let's see within real-time example
how
um it looks when you don't follow the
naming conventions and how the project
will look if you follow the naming
conventions okay
so I'm back in my Tosca project and here
I have opened basically two objects or
you can sit two test cases okay
in the first screen you can see uh this
is the test case which I have built
using naming conventions on the left
hand side
and on the right hand side you will see
uh this is a recorded module okay also
uh test cases also automatically created
now this process will remain same uh
when you scan your modules and create
your test cases directly without
renaming anything these are the default
names which Tosca will pick up okay and
how it decides all these names it
decides on the screen or the
functionality of the application it will
just pick up that name and name your
test case or module accordingly okay
now if you look through uh on the left
hand side okay you will see there is a
proper order of uh test steps which are
mentioned for each test case okay then
there are folders also which basically
group test steps okay and you will see
that they are named properly okay so
looking at this uh structure right or
test case
I can easily follow what's going on in
this test case okay so in the
pre-processing I open a URL in the
processing I first do a registered user
I click on register
um I buffer the email first name last
name I go to the register page and then
um I complete the registration right
also I log out the user I then log in
the user okay
and then I add products to cart I click
on different elements I do shopping I
click on the shopping cart I do a
checkout and you can see uh for checkout
there are different pages and that's why
we have given this uh
uh separator here right so this is for
billing address this for shipping
address this is for shipping method
right so you can make these steps even
more descriptive right you can write um
mailing address checkout you can write
your buffering order details right so
like you're clicking on PDF invoice so
there are all detailed step names right
and then inside this it will have the
module attributes or the values or
verifications whatever we are putting on
right so this is a proper naming
convention right so I'm following a
proper convention for folders for test
steps right and then when there are
common test steps like check out across
different pages I am also giving it with
a separator or I am describing the test
step right what action I'm performing
here right so it could be a click it
could be a verify it could be a buffer
right accordingly I have renamed all the
step okay
so when we come to the uh right part of
it where we haven't followed any naming
conventions we just put together a test
case
um as it was provided by Tosca okay and
by default Tosca will name some of the
test steps based on how it is able to
scan them like open URL okay so it has
named it properly you can still use this
but what about the other ones
like this one is demo webshop uh this
one is again demo webshop okay uh maybe
demo Website login and box is still okay
okay but still not you don't know what
it is doing
and similarly for uh you can see here
checkout okay demo webshot checkout
there are three demo Workshop checkout
right so it's really difficult to make
out for a newcomer or even some other
teammate who has not worked on this
right he will not be able to make out
what this test case is first of all
doing okay what is the test case flow
and which the steps are being used here
okay even looking at the modules it's
very difficult to make out which module
should be used for
um checking out your shipping address or
your billing address or shipping method
right so it's very very difficult
and when you look here it's uh pretty
easy to understand it is reusable
because people will then understand what
uh module what this particular module is
doing right so if I even jump to the
module you will see the module name is
properly named right so check out
billing address
but here uh there is nothing right so
for this it is demo webshot checkout I
don't know whether it is for billing
address or whether it is for payment
details or anything else okay
so this is a brief idea about how naming
conventions can affect your project your
framework and your overall structure
right so it affects a lot of things and
that is why
um this is the first best practice
recommendation which I will provide to
you no matter if you're practicing but
it is very important uh even when you
are working in a project or this could
be one of the questions of if you are
interviewing for a Tosca automation
position
so do keep in mind about this best
practice and do follow a certain naming
convention throughout your project okay
so that's all for this video I hope you
enjoyed it and you learned something new
today
we would love to hear your comments so
please leave a comment uh on the bottom
of this video
and until the next video keep watching
and keep learning